

9167655538 sunil.82ghate@gmail.com A-4103, TenX Habitat, Raymond Reality, JK Gram, Pokharan Road #2, Thane (West), Thane, Maharashtra 400606 India

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

I am Sunil Ghate, have a 12+ years of work experience in various domains viz. e-Learning, Healthcare, Tours and Travels, Fantasy Sports Predictors, Music and Entertainment, Search Engines, Social Networking and Job website, custom build websites etc.

## **SKILLS**

- AWS Services
- Database MySQL, PostgresSQL
- Node Js Express JS

- Frameworks Laravel / CakePHP / Codelgniter / Django
- Angular / React
- HTML5, CSS, ES-6, TypeScript, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap

## **EXPERIENCE**

**Sr. Application Engineer**, **Encurelt Systems Pvt Ltd**, Oct 2023 - Current, Pune Developing APIs catering functional requirements, Coordinating with frontend team for Integrating API, Using code coverage analysis using PHPUnit, Optimizing Queries to enhance product performance, Worked with various AWS services.

Technology Stack: Laravel, MySQL, AWS Cloud Services, Angular 9+

**Technical Lead, LearningMate Solutions**, May 2021 - Jun 2023, Mumbai Coordinating with Client and Stake Holders for requirement gathering, Conducting code review subordinates, Attending Scrum calls for the daily updates. Creating API using TDD approach, writing unit testing

**Technology Stack:** Nodejs + Expressjs Laravel Lumen, MySql RDS, AWS Cloud Services, CI/CD.

**Technical Lead**, **Intense Intellect Pvt Ltd**, Jan 2020 - May 2021, Thane Developing APIs catering functional requirements, Performing Unit testing of code, Making API's for communication of front end with the backend. **Technology Stack:** Nodejs + Expressjs, MySQL - Aurura, AWS Cloud Services.

**Technical Manager**, **LivePools Pvt Ltd**, Jun 2018 - Jan 2020, Mumbai Developing/Enhancing and Maintaining current technology stack. Managing infrastructure on Cloud platform and developing new features in Product. Creating APIs for mobile applications. Involved in Payment Gateway Integration.

**Technology Stack:** Laravel, Codelgniter, ICICI EasyPay Payment Gateway, RazorPay Payment Gateway, MySql RDS, AWS Cloud Services.

Technical Manager, Swasth Foundation, Apr 2017 - Jun 2018, Mumbai

Developing APIs catering functional requirements, Managing entire SaaS based Client Management System includes (Warehouse - Supply chain, Lab Management, Clinic Audits/ Reports, Doctor Consultations, Patient Management).

**Technology Stack:** Codelgniter, PostgreSQL, AWS services, ODK Survey, Redmine Project Management Tool, Mantis Reporting Tool, Telegram Bot API

**Module Lead Engineer**, **OSS Cube Solutions Ltd**, Oct 2014 - Mar 2017, Mumbai Developing/Enhancing and Maintaining flagship B2B and B2C portals of Cox and Kings Tours and Travels.

**Technology Stack:** Custom Framework, MySQL RDS, AWS Services, Flight Booking Engine, WSDL, SOAP, MSSQL

Deputy Manager, Saregama India Ltd, Nov 2012 - Oct 2014, Mumbai

Developing/Enhancing and Maintaining subscription based VAS products. A subscription based content download service offering, Subscription Fallback, Daily WAP Pushes, SMS Keyword Activation, CRBT, Auto-Renewals, Customer Care Admin Tools, Bulk Activation & De-activation tool, IVR activation/Deactivation.

Technology Stack: Core PHP, MySQL, WAP, CRBT, IVR, SMS Keyword, Gateway Integration

Senior Software Engineer, Tricom India Ltd, Jan 2011 - Dec 2012

Developing/Enhancing and Maintaining subscription based VAS products. A subscription based content download service offering, Subscription Fallback, Daily WAP Pushes, SMS Keyword Activation, CRBT, Auto-Renewals, Customer Care Admin Tools, Bulk Activation & De-activation tool, IVR activation/Deactivation.

**Technology Stack:** Core PHP, MySql, WAP, CRBT / IVR, SMS Keyword / Gateway Integration

PHP Developer, blueMango Solutions Pvt. Ltd, Dec 2007 - Jan 2011

Developing various clients websites.

Technology Stack: Smarty Template Engine, Core PHP, CakePHP, MySql

## **EDUCATION**

Diploma in Computer Technology

Jun 2003

Maharashtra State Board of Technical Education - Sangamner

Nashik Divisional Board Jan 2001

SSC Jan 1998

Nashik Divisional Board